Stewart L. Udall papers, 1950-2010
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series II: Department of the Interior, 1961-1972
  - Department of the Interior: Issues and Achievements, Colorado River, 1961-1968
    - Department of the Interior: Issues and Achievements, Colorado River-Correspondence, Reports, Memos, Hearings, etc. Includes Sstatements at House Subcommittee Hearings on Various Bills. January 1966-1968 (Box 168, Folder 1-9)
    - Department of the Interior: Issues and Achievements, Colorado River-Correspondence, Reports, Memos, Hearings, etc. Includes Letter from Joseph Wood Krutch Regarding the Grand Canyon and Material about Indian Problems Rrelating to the Orme Dam and Reservoir. Also Statements at House Subcommittee Hearings on Various Bills. January 1966-1968 (Box 169, Folder 1-11)
    - Department of the Interior: Issues and Achievements, Colorado River-Clippings. 1959-April 1964 (Box 170, Folder 1-11)
    - Department of the Interior: Issues and Achievements, Colorado River-Clippings. See also Box 178 (Oversize) for Additional Clippings. May 1964-1968 (Box 171, Folder 1-11)
    - Department of the Interior: Issues and Achievements, Colorado River-Pacific Southwest Water Plan Report, Summary (Includes Oren Beatty 's Annotated Copy .) August 1963 (Box 172, Folder 1)
    - Department of the Interior: Issues and Achievements, Colorado River-Pacific Southwest Water Plan Report, (Corrected). August 1963 (Box 172, Folder 2)
    - Department of the Interior: Issues and Achievements, Colorado River-Pacific Southwest Water Plan Report, Appendices (Except Bureau of Reclamation). August 1963 (Box 172, Folder 3)
    - Department of the Interior: Issues and Achievements, Colorado River-Pacific Southwest Water Plan Report, Appendices (Bureau of Reclamation; Park Service Variation). August 1963 (Box 172, Folder 4)
    - Department of the Interior: Issues and Achievements, Colorado River-Pacific Southwest Water Plan Report, Printed Report. August 1963 (Box 172, Folder 5)
    - Department of the Interior: Issues and Achievements, Colorado River-Pacific Southwest Water Plan Report, Drafts (Letter of Transmittal to Presient and Reprot of Commisioner of Reclamation). December 1963 (Box 172, Folder 6)
    - Department of the Interior: Issues and Achievements, Colorado River-Pacific Southwest Water Plan Report, Supplemental Information (Bridge Canyon Project, Marble Canyon Project). December 1963 (Box 172, Folder 7)
    - Department of the Interior: Issues and Achievements, Colorado River-Pacific Southwest Water Plan Report, Printed Report. January 1964 (Box 173, Folder 1-2)
    - Department of the Interior: Issues and Achievements, Colorado River-Pacific Southwest Water Plan Report, Appendix (Modified). January 1964 (Box 173, Folder 2)
    - Department of the Interior: Issues and Achievements, Colorado River-Colorado River Basin Project, Miscellaneous and Undated Items. (Box 174, Folder 1)
    - Department of the Interior: Issues and Achievements, Colorado River: Colorado River Storage Project, Miscellaneous and Undated Items. (Box 174, Folder 2)
    - Department of the Interior: Issues and Achievements, Colorado River-Pacific Southwest Water Plan, Miscellaneous, Papers, Mostly Undated. (Box 174, Folder 3)
    - Department of the Interior: Issues and Achievements, Colorado River-Central Arizona Project, Miscellaneous Material. (Box 174, Folder 4-5)
    - Department of the Interior: Issues and Achievements, Colorado River-Miscellaneous Undated Notes by Stewart Udall and Oren Beatty. (Box 174, Folder 6)
    - Department of the Interior: Issues and Achievements, Colorado River- Sidney Kartus, Background Material, 1956-1958 (Box 174, Folder 7)
    - Department of the Interior: Issues and Achievements, Colorado River-Arizona Game and Fish Department: Summary of the Fish and Wildlife Features of the Central Arizona Project and the Pacific Southwest Water Plan. February 1965 (Box 174, Folder 8)
    - Department of the Interior: Issues and Achievements, Colorado River-Miscellaneous Material. 1956-1965 (Box 174, Folder 9)
      Los Angeles, California, Department of Water and Power- Snake-Colorado Project: A Plan to Transport Surplus Columbia River Basin Water to the Arid Pacific Southwest. October 1963..
      Loftus, Brian J., Marble Canyon Project. A graduate paper presented in partial fulfillment...for the Degree Master of Science in Economics, College of Business Administration, Arizona State University. May 1963.
      Arizona Highways, June 1958. Issue devoted to the Colorado River.
      "An Ode - From California, " Anonymous poem about the Colorado River controversy.
      "Registration List CRBCP ."
      Crampton, C. Gregory, Outline History of the Glen Canyon Region, 1776-1922. University of Utah, Department of Anthropology. Anthropological Papers, no.42. September 1959 (Glen Canyon Series No. 9)
      Crampton, C. Gregory: Historical Sites in Glen Canyon, Mouth of San Juan River to Lee's Ferry. University of Utah, Department of Anthropology. Anthropological Papers, no.46. June 1960. (Glen Canyon Series no.12)
  - Department of the Interior: Addresses, Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies, 1961-1972
    - Department of the Interior: Card File of "Arizona Names & Addresses, A-L." (Box 175)
    - Department of the Interior: Card File of "Arizona Names & Addresses, M-Z." (Box 176)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies. The Following are Oversize Items which Relate to Additonal Materials in the Boxes Indicated. 1961-1967 (Box 177)
      National Coal Policy Conference, Washington, D.C. Program and LP Record of songs sung by the Baltimore & Ohio Glee Club at the dinner, March 29, 1961. See also Box 92
      Circus Saints & Sinners Club Luncheon, Washington, D.C.. Large Autographed Memento of this Occasion Honoring Stewart Udall. as "Fall Guy," June 28, 1961
      Trip to Japan. Framed and inscribed photo of Stewart Udall on Mount Fiji, November 5, 1961. See also Box 193
      Ground-breaking ceremonies for Sanford Dam, Canadian River Project, Amarillo, Texas, Clippings, June 30, 1962. See also Box 193
      Dedication of Navajo Dam, Navajo Trail Highway, and Four Corners Marker, New Mexico,Clippings, September 15-16, 1962. See also Box 104
      Trip to Africa. Color photo of Stewart Udall on the Climb up Mount Kilimanjaro, September 1963. See also Box 124
      President Johnson’s Inauguration, Washington, D.C. Clippings, color photo, January 30, 1965. See also Box 124
      Visit to Saline Water Conversion Plant with Visiting Ambassadors, Freeport, Texas, Clippings, August 4, 1965. See also Box 124
      Trip to Georgia and the Cumberland Islands, Clippings, November 4-5, 1965. See also Box 125
      Hofstra University Natural Beauty Conference (Hempstead, New York) and Honorary Degree to Stewart Udall, Clipping, May 28, 1966. See also Box 198. Honors & Awards
      Lake Erie Water Pollution Control Enforcement Conference (Cleveland, Ohio) and the Tour of Cuyahoga River Valley Area, Clippings, June 22, 1966. See also Box 131
      Dedication of Visitor Center, Cabrillo National Monument, San Diego, California, October 27, 1966. Color photo with letter of transmittal. See also Box 132
      President’s State of the Union Message. Color photo with letter of transmittal, January 10, 1967. See also Box 135
      Trip to the Middle East. Clippings, photos, FEbruary 2-12, 1967. See also Box 136
      Dedication of Coal-to-Gasoline Pilot Plant: Cresap, West Virginia. Photo of Stewart Udall and others May 27, 1967
    - Department of the Interior: Miscellaneous Clippings and Drawings. The following are Oversize items which relate to additional materials in the boxes indicated. 1961-1967 (Box 178)
      Burton Silverman’s original Illustrations for article about Stewart Udall: "Vacation Spots Off the Beaten Track," Newsweek, July 3, 1961. See Box 90
      Clippings,Cabinet Selection, December 1960. See also Box 80
      Clippings, President John F. Kennedy; various topics, various dates
      Clippings, Power,Passamaquoddy Tidal Power Project, Maine, 1963. See also Box 159
      Clippings, Strip Mining, 1960. See also Box 155
      Clippings, Viet Nam and Lyndon B. Johnson, 1967. See also Box 135
      Clippings, Water, Colorado River, Central Arizona Project, Grand Canyon Dams, Salt River Project, 1963-1967. See Box 162 and Boxes 170-171
      Clippings, Wilderness Bill, 1962. See also Box 162
      Oil Shale, 1967. See also Box 157
      Parks & Recreation, 1961-1962. See also Box 158
      "Student Committee for Kennedy" ad, 1968
      Redwoods, 1967. See also Box 155
      Dobie, J. Frank, "A White House Visit," 1964
      Frost, Robert, Article about this letters, 1964
      Sandburg, Carl, Article about his farm at Flat Rock, North Carolina: See also Box 190
      National Congress of American Indians: "To the People Who Have Settled These United States," Broadside,
      Proposed Tocks Island Dam, Delaware River and Tocks Island National Recreation Area, New Jersey, color drawing. See also Box 156
    - Department of the Interior: Miscellaneous Gifts. 1961-1962 (Box 179)
      Wood Plaque with ceramic head of Lincoln, presented by the Jaycees of Rockport, Indiana, at the Dedication of Lincoln’s Boyhood National Memorial, July 10, 1962. See Box 103.
      Ifilwood Plaque presented by Bill Daniel, Governor of Guam, at the Annual Governors Conference held in Hawaii, July 18, 1961
      Alaskan Flag presented by William Egan, Governor of Alaska
      Reproduction of Arizona’s Proclamation of Statehood, signed by President William H. Taft, February 14, 1912. From the First National Bank of Arizona
      Advertising Poster of Mescalero Apache’s Sierra Blanca Ski Area in New Mexico. From Wendell Chino, President of the Mescalero Apache Tribe
      American Flag, 48 stars
    - Department of the Interior: Miscellaneous Gifts. 1959-1965- (Box 180)
      Wood Plaque "from your friends in the Wabash Valley Association," New Harmony, Indiana, August 21, 1965. See Box 124.
      Mounted Indian Relics (arrowheads, stone axehead) presented to Stewart Udall by the people of Louisa County, Iowa, 1965. "One page in history from the proposed Toolesboro National Historic Site "
      Framed Copy of the "Conservation Pledge," from Outdoor Life Magazine, February 23, 1965. See Box 196
      Medallion from Friends of the Serengeti: A Group interested in saving great Parklands in Tanzania
      Medallion commemorating the placing of the "keystone" section of the St. Louis Gateway Arch. October 28, 1965
      Medallion commemorating the National 4-H Conference, Washington, D.C. June 13-19, 1959
      Official Medallion, Jefferson National Expansion Memorial, 1964
      Original Japanese Painting by Keisen Yamaguchi, goldfish painter
      Two photographs of Japanese officials (one identified as Mr. Shigemasa, Minister of Agriculture and Forestry, 1962) in silver frames and special boxes
      Key to the City of Scranton, Pennsylvania: James J. Walsh, Mayor
      4-cent Homestead Act Commemorative Postage Stamp, First Day Cover
      5-cent Migratory Bird Treaty Commemorative Postage Stamp: First Day of Issue, March 19, 1966
      Unidentified gavel
    - Department of the Interior Finale: Appointment Schedule and Travel Accounts. January 1969 (Box 181, Folder 1)
    - Department of the Interior Finale: "Hail and Farewell," Department of the Interior Staff. 1969 (Box 181, Folder 2)
    - Department of the Interior Finale: "Hail and Farewell," Congress. 1969 (Box 181, Folder 3)
    - Department of the Interior Finale: "Hail and Farewell," General. 1969 (Box 181, Folder 4-5)
    - Department of the Interior Finale: Department of the Interior, Miscellaneous Correspondence. Includes the Naming of the Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Stadium, and Letter from Ethel Kennedy. January 1969 (Box 181, Folder 6)
    - Department of the Interior Finale: Last Day. January 20, 1969 (Box 181, Folder 7)
    - Department of the Interior Finale: Press Conferences. Includes Tape Recording. January 9, 1969 (Box 181, Folder 8)
    - Department of the Interior Finale: Television Programs. 1969 (Box 181, Folder 9)
    - Department of the Interior Finale: Invitations. 1969 (Box 181, Folder 10)
    - Department of the Interior Finale: National Tribute to Earl Warren, Supreme Court Justice, Correspondence, Plans. June 1969 (Box 181, Folder 11)
    - Department of the Interior Finale: National Tribute to Earl Warren, Supreme Court Justice, Photos, Program, Stewart Udall Notes, Clippings. 1969 (Box 181, Folder 12)
    - Department of the Interior Finale: Trip to Europe. July 1969 (Box 181, Folder 13)
    - Department of the Interior Finale: Stewart Udall and President Johnson. 1969 (Box 182, Folder 1)
    - Department of the Interior Finale: President Johnson and the National Monument Proclamations. July 1968 - January 20, 1969 (Box 182, Folder 2-3)
    - Department of the Interior Finale: Governor Hickel and the Transition, Correspondence, Stewart Udall Notes. 1969 (Box 182, Folder 4)
    - Department of the Interior Finale: Governor Hickel and the Transition, Clippings. 1969 (Box 182, Folder 5)
    - Department of the Interior Finale: "Hickel Smear" regarding the Virgin Islands and Overview. 1968-1972 (Box 182, Folder 6)
    - Department of the Interior Finale: Stewart Udall Personal and Miscellaneous Correspondence. Includes Letter from Paul Horgan about the Possibility of a Stewart Udall’s Portrait Painted by Peter Hurd. 1969 (Box 182, Folder 7)
    - Department of the Interior Finale: Testimony before Various Congressional Subcommittees. 1969 (Box 182, Folder 8)
    - Department of the Interior Finale: Speeches,Various. 1969 (Box 182, Folder 9)
      Testimonial Dinner honoring Stewart Udall, Washington, DC, January 3, 1969
      Joint Meeting of the League of Women Voters of Arizona & the American Association of University Women, Phoenix, Arizona, February 1969
      University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan, March 24, 1969
      State University of New York, Albany, New York, June 8
      "The Value Revolution" - Oberlin College, Oberlin, Ohio, September 15, 1969
      South Florida Chapter of the American Institute of Architects Symposium, aboard Ship bound for Nassau, September 1969
      Twentieth Annual P.I.P. Think Shop Conference; Washington, DC, September 25, 1969
      Madison Civics Club, Madison, Wisconsin, October 18, 1969
      Southern Colorado State College Science Symposium, Pueblo, Colorado, December 8, 1969
    - Department of the Interior Finale: Stewart Udall Clippings. 1969 (Box 182, Folder 10)
    - Department of the Interior Finale: Miscellaneous Clippings. 1969 (Box 182, Folder 11)
- Series III: Activity Files, 1970-1977
  - Activity Files: Stewart Udall Personal and Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1970 (Box 183, Folder 1)
  - Activity Files: Yale University Lectures, Correspondence, Clippings. 1969-1970 (Box 183, Folder 2)
  - Activity Files: Yale University Lectures, Stewart Udall Notes, Background Material, etc. 1969-1970 (Box 183, Folder 3)
  - Activity Files: Speaking Engagement Brochures. 1970's (Box 183, Folder 4)
  - Activity Files: University of Wisconsin Commencement, Madison. June 8, 1970 (Box 183, Folder 5)
  - Activity Files: 1st National Congress on Optimum Population and Environment, Chicago, Illinois. June 9, 1970 (Box 183, Folder 6)
  - Activity Files: 137th Annual Meeting of the American Association for the Advancement of Science, Chicago, Illinois. December 30, 1970 (Box 183, Folder 7)
  - Activity Files: Speeches, Various. 1970 (Box 183, Folder 8)
    Allegheny College, Meadville, Pennsylvania
    Montgomery Conference, University of Nebraska, Lincoln
    University of Maine Environmental Teach-In, Orono?, Maine
    Weber State College, Ogden, Utah
    New School for Social Research, New York City. Guest Lecturer at a Class in "Population and Family Planning ," January 14, 1970
    Testimonial Dinner honoring Morris K. Udall, Tucson, Arizona, January 30, 1970
    Environmental Conference at University of Tennessee, Chattanooga, February 13, 1970
    Texas Christian University, Fort Worth. Earth Day Speaker, April 25, 1970
    Environmental Awareness Forum at University of South Florida, Tampa, May 6, 1970
    20th International Design Conference, Aspen, Colorado, June 1970
    Elmhurst College Centennial Year Celebration, Elmhurst, Illinois, September 9, 1970
    Young Democrats Dinner, Norfolk, Virginia, September 26, 1970
  - Activity Files: Speeches, Various. 1970 (Box 183, Folder 9)
    Democratic Fund-raising Dinner, Wilmington, Delaware, October 5, 1970
    Bradley University Lecture Art Series, Peoria, Illinois, October 14, 1970
    17th Arizona Town Hall, Grand Canyon, October 19, 1970
    Indiana University Lycea Dinner, Bloomington, October 25, 1970
    Georgetown College, Georgetown, Kentucky, October 26, 1970
    Ball State University, Muncie, Indiana, October 27, 1970
    Wichita State University Eisenhower Lecture Series, Wichita, Kansas, November 12, 1970
    Symposium on the Environment, New York City, November 1970
  - Activity Files: Speeches, Undated, Unidentified, Fragments. 1970's (Box 183, Folder 10)
  - Activity Files: Statements Before Various Congressional Committees. 1970 (Box 183, Folder 11)
  - Activity Files: Sears Detergent Endorsement. 1970 (Box 183, Folder 12)
  - Activity Files: Poll Survey for Possible Stewart Udall Senate Campaign. 1970 (Box 183, Folder 13)
  - Activity Files: "Udall vs. Fannin: the 1970 Non-Campaign." 1970 (Box 183, Folder 14)
  - Activity Files: Clippings, Stewart Udall. 1970 (Box 183, Folder 15)
  - Activity Files: Clippings, Miscellaneous. 1970 (Box 183, Folder 16)
  - Activity Files: Stewart Udall Personal and Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1971 (Box 184, Folder 1)
  - Activity Files: Speech, 50th Anniversary of Cleveland Clinic Foundation, Cleveland, Ohio. February 16, 1971 (Box 184, Folder 2)
  - Activity Files: Speeches, Various. 1971 (Box 184, Folder 3)
    First Arkansas Environmental Congress, 1971
    Western Carolina University, Cullowhee, North Carolina, January 11, 1971
    Ethics-Ecology Conference at Bemidji State College, Bemidji, Minnesota, February 11, 1971
    University of Colorado American Heritage Lecture Series, Boulder, March 3, 1971
    Midland Cooperatives, Inc., Convention, Minneapolis, Minnesota, March 23, 1971
    University of Rhode Island, Providence, April 21, 1971
    University of Cincinnati, (Ohio) and Raymond Walters General and Technical College (Blue Ash, Ohio) Earth Week Talks, April 22, 1971
    Hamilton College, Clinton, New York, May 30, 1971
    University of Oregon Law School, Eugene, September 25, 1971
    Northeast Louisiana University, Monroe, September 27, 1971
    Arapaho County Democratic Party’s Annual Dinner, Denver, Colorado, October 16, 1971
    Canadian Institute of Mining and Metallurgy Annual Meeting, October 25, 1971
    Curry College, Milton, Massachusetts, December 7, 1971
    Colorado Society of Architects Annual Meeting, Golden, late 1971
  - Activity Files: Statement at Public Hearing on the Trans-Alaska Pipeline. February 17, 1971 (Box 184, Folder 4)
  - Activity Files: Statement Before House Transportation Subcommittee Regarding the SST. March 2, 1971 (Box 184, Folder 5)
  - Activity Files: Statement Before the White House Commission on Population Growth and the American Future. April 14, 1971 (Box 184, Folder 6)
  - Activity Files: Statements Before Various Congressional Subcommittees. 1971 (Box 184, Folder 7)
  - Activity Files: "The Shoplifting Caper. " Includes letters from Edward Kennedy and Theodore Sorensen. January 1971 (Box 184, Folder 8)
  - Activity Files: Television Programs. 1971 (Box 184, Folder 9)
  - Activity Files: International Conference on Environmental Future, Helsinki, Finland. June 27-July 3, 1971 (Box 184, Folder 10-11)
  - Activity Files: Clippings, Stewart Udall. 1971 (Box 184, Folder 12)
  - Activity Files: Clippings, Miscellaneous. 1971 (Box 184, Folder 13)
  - Activity Files: Stewart Udall Personal and Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1972 (Box 185, Folder 1)
  - Activity Files:: Speech, 2nd Vail Symposium, Colorado. August 4-5, 1972 (Box 185, Folder 2)
  - Activity Files: Speech, Academy of Medicine of Cleveland & Cuyahoga County Medical Society-William E. Lower Lecture, Cleveland, Ohio. November 8, 1972 (Box 185, Folder 3)
  - Activity Files: Speeches, Various. 1972 (Box 185, Folder 4)
    Sierra Club Conference on Electric Power, January 1972
    University of Arizona, Tucson, February 7, 1972
    Arizona State University, 11th Annual Grady Gammage Memorial Lecture, Tempe, February 16, 1972
    Delaware Council of Engineering Societies Annual Meeting, Du Pont Country Club, February 22, 1972
    Texas Tech, Lubbock, April 6, 1972
    North Central Michigan College, Petoskey. Earth Day Speaker, April 26, 1972
    Committee for Green Foothills 10th Anniversary Dinner, Los Altos, California, May 19, 1972
    Citizens Committee for Conservation, St. Louis, Missouri, May 25, 1972
    Montana Bar Association, June 23, 1972
    Lutheran Church in America Convention, Dallas, Texas, July 2, 1972
    Institute on Futurology, July 26m 1972
    World University Commencement, San Juan, Puerto Rico, July 28, 1972. See Box 201a: Honors & Awards
    National Recreation and Park Association Convention, Anaheim, California, October 4, 1972
    Iowa Central Community College, Fort Dodge. Forum Series on the Environment, November 15, 1972
    Indiana University, School of Law; Bloomington, November 1972
    Annual Northwestern Management Conference, December 7- 8, 1972
  - Activity Files: Testimony Before Senate Public Works Subcommittee on Roads. May 26, 1972 (Box 185, Folder 5)
  - Activity Files: Campaign Fund for the Environment. 1972 (Box 185, Folder 6)
  - Activity Files: McGovern Campaign, Stewart Udall Notes. 1972 (Box 185, Folder 7)
  - Activity Files: McGovern Campaign, Defense and Foreign Policy. 1972 (Box 185, Folder 8)
  - Activity Files: McGovern Campaign, "Vision of a Mature America" Speeches. 1972 (Box 185, Folder 9-10)
  - Activity Files: McGovern Campaign, General Clippings. 1972 (Box 185, Folder 11)
  - Activity Files: Clippings; Stewart Udall and Miscellaneous. 1972 (Box 185, Folder 12)
  - Activity Files: Stewart Udall Personal and Miscellaneous Correspondence. Includes Letters from Roger Morton and Archibald MacLeish. 1973 (Box 186, Folder 1)
  - Activity Files: Speech, Linfield College, McMinnville, Oregon. January 26-27, 1973 (Box 186, Folder 2)
  - Activity Files: Speech, University of Utah, Salt Lake City-First Annual Reynolds Lecture in Natural History. November 16, 1973 (Box 186, Folder 3)
  - Activity Files: Speeches. January-August 1973 (Box 186, Folder 4)
    NEOCON V, Baylor University, Waco, Morehead State University, Kentucky, University of Alabama, Birmingham
    American Society for Public Administration, Hawaii, January 8, 1973
    University of Hawaii, January 9, 1973
    National Collegiate Athletic Association Convention, Chicago, Illinois, January 12, 1973. See Box 201a: Honors & Awards
    Dedication of Alameda Creek Trail, California, January 13, 1973
    Drury College, Springfield, Missouri, March 5, 1973
    Nebraska State Education Association Meeting, Chadron, March 15, 1973
    National Wildlife Federation Meeting, Washington, DC, April 1973
    Zero Population Growth, 5th Annual Meeting, Boston, Massachusetts, April 14, 1973
    University of California at San Diego. Wilderness and Contemporary Man Seminar, May 8, 1973
    Alaska Methodist University (Anchorage) Statewide Alaska Humanities Forum
    June 14- Colorado Municipal League; Colorado Springs, June 5-6, 1973
    American Bar Association, Washington, DC, August 1973
  - Activity Files: Speeches. September-December 1973 (Box 186, Folder 5)